Daniel Peterschmidt

[w] http://danielpeterschmidt.com

[e] dpete93@gmail.com

[c] 760.473.7106

BIO

A passionate artist with experience in nearly all aspects of digital production, including graphic design, audio production, web design/ development, writing, photography, and filmmaking. In the summer of 2014, studied abroad in Taiwan and mastered conversational fluency in Mandarin. Expanded skill-set in a professional context at NPR as a Product Development intern and continues to do so at the public radio show Science Friday as a Digital Producer.

Highly motivated; loves working on teams in a passionate, creative, and collaborative environments.

LANGUAGES

HTML5 CSS3 Javascript PHP MySQL

TOOLS

Adobe Creative Suite Sketch Sublime Text 3 Bootstrap 3 Google Analytics

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF PUGET SOUND

Bachelor of Arts, Chinese Language and Culture Minor: Computer Science

Fall 2014

EXPERIENCE

Digital Producer Science Friday February 2016 - Present

New York City



Podcast Producer #LOVEGASM Podcast, Summers Love Company February 2016 - Present

New York City

Coordinate, edit, and distribute narrative episodes centered around women's sexual health and intimacy. If needed, I arrange and record interviews. I work with the host, Summers McKay, to structure the episode's story arc and determine who we need to interview. Prior to an episode's release, I make graphic "quotables" based on quotes from interviews to market on social media.

Web Developer/Designer Freelance

November 2013 - January 2016

Washington, D.C.

Created mobile responsive web sites using Wordpress for clients, learned new languages and skills based on the job, communicated clearly and consistently with clients to ensure that goals were established and met on time, and if necessary, coordinated client's social media presences on Facebook and Twitter to ensure cohesive brand message.

Product Development Intern NPR

January 2015 - May 2015

Washington, D.C.

Designed standard card for NPR's Reddit AMAs for social media distribution, created original promotional art for several NPR podcasts, implemented visual and UX upgrades to NPR's iTunes homepage, wrote about social and digital media trends for the NPR Social Media Desk blog, and analyzed audience behavior and analytics over multiple social networks for NPR's podcasts.



#L**₩V**ĔĞÂSM



